OKAFOR EMELDER

FRONTEND DEVELOPER

L +234-80375-88098

personal-portfolio

github-link

(in) linkedin-link

Lagos, Nigeria

I am a frontend developer with demonstrated experience in building scalable websites by translating UI/UX prototypes into maintainable and responsive user interface JavaScript(ES6), React/API, CSS and CSS frameworks, HTML5, Git and other technologies for developing interactive frontend applications. I'm a fast learner, a team player and can work independently on any task to arrive at a workable and most profitable end point.

WORK EXPERIENCES

Frontend Developer

2021-2022

Ascendancy, Lagos, Nigeria

- Designed effective, maintainable and scalable user interfaces for clients and brands.
- Maintained and updated websites according to new design requirements to boost performance.
- Collaborated with backend engineers to define solution requirements for applicable development variables.
- Identified and implemented dynamic web solutions in accordance to company standards and best practices.
- Partnered with UI/UX design teams to transform clients wireframes from conception to implementation.
- Kept track of user stories/bugs in GitHub projects and conducting 2 hours of sprint planning and sprint retrospectives per week.

Adhoc Technical Staff

2016 - 2020

Rural Electrification Agency of Nigeria

- Tested and maintained recommended software improvements.
- Renewable energy system installations.
- Researched, designed, implemented and managed software programs.
- Identified areas for modification in existing programs and subsequently developing these modifications.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Libraries/Frameworks

- HTML/HTML5
- CSS/CSS3
- JavaScript(ES6)
- ReactJs/Context API
- Styled-Components
- TailwindCSS
- SASS
- Bootstrap
- Material UI

Tools

- Git/Github/Gitlab/BitBucket
- Figma/ Zeplin
- Netlify/Vercel/AWS

SOFT SKILLS

- Excellent communication skills in English.
- Fast learner and team player.
- Attention to details.
- · Able to think fast and critically.

EDUCATION

AltSchool Africa 2022-2023

• Diploma(Frontend Engineering)

Nnamdi Azikiwe University, Anambra State, Nigeria 2009-2015

• B.Eng (Electrical Engineering) 2nd Class Honors-Upper Division